<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>180 Stocks</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://180stocks.github.io/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><item><title>Day 11</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-11/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The company I studied today was &lt;a href="http://www.piindustries.com/"&gt;PI Industries Ltd&lt;/a&gt;. It was part of the peer comparison in CRISIL's report on Dhanuka Industries which I studied on &lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/day-6/"&gt;day 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has issued new shares during each of the last 4 years. Thus it required some efforts to prepare the adjusted net profit figures and to evaluate the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="PI Industries adjusted net profits" src="http://180stocks.github.io/static/uploads/pi-adjusted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has two main verticals. In domestic market it sells the agri-input products (agro-chemicals, fertilizers and plant nutrients), and does the contract research and manufacturing (CRAMS) for its foreign clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, the company raised 117 crores through a qualified-institutional-placement (QIP), by issuing the shares at 609.60 (dilution of 8%). The funds being used to setup a new facility at Jambusar SEZ to &lt;em&gt;"provide a fillip to the export volumes."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the company has had an asset-turnover of around 4 times (current net block is of 480 crores). If the capacities are utilized and the company is able to get the export orders, then it can see a turnover of around 2000 crores in a few years (FY 2013's turnover was 1245 crores and FY14Q1 turnover was 400 crores).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current market capitalization of the company is 1758 crores. Based on the annualized earnings of last quarter, the company is at a forward PE of around 10-12 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn't a high margin of safety and visibility at these levels, but it is a stock I will keep an eye on.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-15:day-11/</guid></item><item><title>Day 10</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-10/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I shuffled through several companies trading at their multi-year lows. Some businesses were pure cyclical and some were too complex to understand. In the end &lt;a href="http://www.iclbelting.com/index.html"&gt;International Conveyors Ltd&lt;/a&gt;. looked interesting. Its market capitalization has been on a down-slide from 250 crore levels to 67 crores, while the top-line has shown a consistent growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company is &lt;em&gt;"one of the country’s largest PVC Belting exporters to USA and Canada. Company enjoys India’s leading 40% share in the PVC Conveyor Belting market for underground mines. The company’s manufacturing facilities are located in Aurangabad, Maharashtra that has the largest manufacturing facility in the world."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began with the company's 2007 annual report. That year the top-line had grown by 39% and the bottom-line had more than doubled. Company had an impressive order-book of over 20 crores (40% of 2007s sales) and it expected &lt;em&gt;"to report two years of straight growth: a 40 per cent revenue increase in 2007-08 followed by 40 per cent in 2008-09."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance sheet reported an increase in loan from 13 crores to 30 crores. Simultaneously, there was an increase in the gross block from 7 crores to 26 crores. That year, the company had added 19 crores of windmills funded out of debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results were seen in over the next couple of years. While the topline did grow over 30% in 2008, the bottom-line decreased by half under the interest pressure. Subsequently, in 2009, the company raised money through warrants to pay back the loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the 2012 annual report, the loan has again risen to 39 crores (from 19 crores in 2010) and another windmill of 8.74 crores has been added to the gross block.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-13:day-10/</guid></item><item><title>Day 9</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-9/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I studied &lt;a href="http://www.dynemic.com/"&gt;Dynemic Products Ltd&lt;/a&gt;, which can be an example of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.valuebull.com/Cigar+Butts"&gt;cigar butt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This company has a market capitalization of 16 crores. It is &lt;em&gt;"into manufacturing of food color, lake color, D&amp;amp;C colors, salt free dyes, dye intermediates which is used as an essential ingredient of food, drug, cosmetic, personal care and FMCG industry."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a highly competitive business due to its commodity nature.
Company's 10-year-average growth rate is only 17% in-spite of a major
expansion in 2008 (company came up with an IPO in 2006). There have been constant margin pressures over last few years and the operating margins have fallen from 16% to 11% levels. The 10-year-average profit growth rate has been only 14.58%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 annual report, the company says the lower margins are &lt;em&gt;"largely attributed to MEE plant, which has incurred Rs.4.57 cores on working capital this year and Rs.47 lacs on fixed assets which is a step ahead for pollution control and GPCB norms."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MEE plant is a regulatory requirement and impacts the company negatively as unorganized/small competitors are not required to comply with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the valuation side, the stock looks over-beaten. The company came up with an IPO in 2006 at Rs.35 (valuing the company at 39 crores and 10 times its earnings). The company has paid consistent dividends of around 1.5 crores each year and provides a dividend yield of 9%. The current price is around half its book value and the rupee depreciation should be a big positive for the company (as 70% of the company's revenue are from exports).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would still give the company a miss primarily because of slow growth, low return ratios, lower booked depreciation and highly &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=532707#quarters"&gt;volatile quarters&lt;/a&gt;. Though the stock returns look attractive in micro-caps, I would prefer &lt;a href="|filenam|/day-7.md"&gt;Gulshan Polyols&lt;/a&gt; over it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-12:day-9/</guid></item><item><title>Day 8</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-8/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to study the companies which are leaders in their fields. One such company which often comes up on screens is &lt;a href="http://www.himatsingka.com/"&gt;Himatsingka Seide Ltd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://crisil.com/Ratings/RatingList/RatingDocs/HimatsingkaSeideLimited_120413.html"&gt;CRISIL's report&lt;/a&gt; describes them the best:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Himatsingka group has been a leading manufacturer and the largest exporter of silk and silk-blended drapery and upholstery fabrics in India for the past eight years. The group, backed by its team of designers in India, the US, and Europe, offers more than 10,000 products, and can create 1500 products annually. It has further established itself in the home textiles segment, where it was already present with high-end drapery and upholstery products, through its bed linen business. The bed linen operations, which are fully integrated with a manufacturing unit at Hassan (Karnataka), three acquired global distribution companies, and a retail arm with 14 stores, account for about 90 per cent of the Himatsingka group’s total revenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exciting thing about the company is its &lt;strong&gt;market capitalization of just 273 crores&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=514043&amp;amp;con=1&amp;amp;c=152#pl"&gt;top-line and EBIDT levels&lt;/a&gt; have been pretty strong in comparison to the valuations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, the company raised money through GDRs and the net worth stood at around 600 crores (and has stayed at around same levels until 2013). Since then, the company has done aggressive overseas acquisitions which tightly integrates with the company's production. This has led to the creation of 532 crores of (intangible) goodwill in the balance sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The real problem has been the derivate losses on the company's foreign currency contracts. In 2009, the company posted a loss of 74 crores.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Extract from the 2009 annual report)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The financial performance during the year has been primarily impacted by a Rs. 43 crore loss attributable to closure / provisioning on account of foreign exchange derivative contracts, a Rs 18 crore loss incurred on account of foreign exchange translation/realization and a loss of Rs. 15 crore on account of the stabilization of the Bed Linen plant in the first half of the financial year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not sure whether the loss was a one time item or can repeat again (considering there is again a similar volatility in exchange rates). There is still a foreign currency loan of $136 lacs, hedging contracts outstanding of more than $200 lacs and a little extra-volatility can take the bottom-line in any direction. As there are far too many components involved, I convinced myself to watch this stock only from a distance, even though it looked very attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still wanted to know why the losses occurred and how does accounting work in foreign exchange contracts. 2008's &lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/static/uploads/dollar-chart.jpg"&gt;dollar vs rupee&lt;/a&gt; chart told a part of the story and &lt;a href="http://www.sify.com/finance/india-incs-experiment-with-derivatives-news-derivatives-jegr80jdacg.html"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; provided a good commentary. But the real gem was &lt;a href="http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/todays-paper/tp-opinion/accounting-of-derivative-losses/article1621825.ece"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dolphy D'Souza which explained the hedge accounting, knock-in &amp;amp; knockouts and the role of Swiss Franc.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-08:day-8/</guid></item><item><title>Day 7</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-7/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I studied &lt;a href="http://www.gulshanindia.com/"&gt;Gulshan Polyols&lt;/a&gt; today. This company is amongst the largest producers &lt;sup id="fnref:producers"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:producers" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of sorbitol and calcium carbonate in India. The interesting thing about the company is its slow-growing-boring-business on one side, and the extreme low valuation on the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 50% of the company's revenue come from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sorbitol"&gt;sorbitol&lt;/a&gt; and 40% from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calcium_carbonate"&gt;calcium carbonate&lt;/a&gt;. The company has a clientele of large corporates &lt;sup id="fnref:clientele"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:clientele" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; including Colgate, Unilever, Asian Paints etc. But the revenue growth has been nominal at 7-15%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the valuations side, the company is available at a &lt;strong&gt;market capitalization of just 48 crores&lt;/strong&gt;. There is a cash of 28 crores on the &lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/bseplus/annualreport/532457/5324570313.pdf"&gt;balance sheet&lt;/a&gt;, and the last year's net profit was 24 crores. Cash flow from operations for each of the last 5 years has been more than 20 crores. Company has been consistently paying the dividends and I really couldn't dig anything negative about the management (i.e. no subsidiaries, related party transactions, preferential allotments, windmills or insider trading). The company also has 6 plants (in 5 states), 150 acres of land and has a workforce of over 1500 employees. &lt;a href="http://www.careratings.com/Portals/0/CareAdmin/CompanyFiles/PR/GULSHAN%20POLYOLS%20LTD.-01082013.pdf"&gt;CARE&lt;/a&gt; has consistently given a &lt;a href="http://www.careratings.com/Portals/0/CareAdmin/CompanyFiles/PR/GULSHAN%20POLYOLS%20LTD.-01082013.pdf"&gt;A/A1 rating&lt;/a&gt; to the company's borrowings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the large negatives, I could only find the low rate of taxation. Will try to collect more details about it and do some groundwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:producers"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Gulshan Polyols and &lt;a href="http://www.kasyap.com/"&gt;Kasyap&lt;/a&gt; claim to be the largest producers of Sorbitol in India&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:producers" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:clientele"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/day-3/"&gt;Previous post&lt;/a&gt; relating to companies with large clients but slow growth.&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:clientele" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-06:day-7/</guid></item><item><title>Day 6</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-6/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I picked up &lt;a href="http://www.dhanuka.com/"&gt;Dhanuka Agritech Ltd&lt;/a&gt;. It &lt;em&gt;"manufactures a wide range of agro-chemicals like herbicides, insecticides, fungicides, miticides, plant growth regulators in various forms – liquid, dust, powder and granules. The Company has a pan-India presence through its marketing offices in all major states in India, with a network of more than 7,000 distributors/ dealers"&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years the company has had a good steady growth of around 15% in top-line and 25% in bottom-line. The company introduces new brands and products each year, and has many technical tie-ups with international companies like Nissan, DuPont, Dow, FMC etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing in the company's 2013 annual report was its expansion plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Company has bought 10 acres of land at Keshwana in Rajasthan for setting up a new manufacturing unit of International standards with maximum automation. The expected capex is to the tune of Rs.45-50 crores. The unit is expected to be operational by 2014 and will triple the existing manufacturing capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Company has been allotted approx. 1,50,000 sq.mtr. Industrial plot in Dahej, which is a Chemical zone in Gujarat, for future expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would help your Company to achieve its objective of robust growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically the company has had a very good asset-turnover ratio (with sales of 646 crores on the net block of just 40 crores). The reason has been the 'formulation' manufacturing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Formulation' manufacturers: These are manufacturers of final product from technical grade pesticides (the usable form of pesticides). This is quite an asset light model and serves mostly B2C segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above expansion can be a big trigger if the capacities are utilized. The company has also signed Amitabh Bachan as its brand ambassador recently. This too may provide a good growth going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="390" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/mSy1HwUEWYI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company's current market capitalization is 675 crores. The business has a good ROE of over 25%, but the stock price is 2.5 times its book value. The major risk is the company's import exposure of more than 30 percent of its raw material costs. It will be interesting to see if the company is able to pass on the recent rupee depreciation in its price sensitive market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/news_html_files/news_attachment/2013/Dhanuka-Agritech_CRISIL_110713.pdf"&gt;CRISIL's report&lt;/a&gt; has reported the company as fairly valued at the current levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding &lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/day-5/"&gt;Ashiana Housing's value of constructed area&lt;/a&gt;, I couldn't find the details regarding it in the given reports. Will try to send a mail regarding it to the company.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-05:day-6/</guid></item><item><title>Day 5</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The two stocks, Financial Technologies and MCX, had another &lt;a href="http://capitalmind.in/2013/08/nsel-might-have-dummy-stocks-in-what-seems-to-be-a-financing-scheme/"&gt;free-fall&lt;/a&gt; today. It was tempting to analyze them. The two primary questions were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How impactful can be the damage of NSEL for Financial Tech?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is MCX falling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding answer to both of the above was almost impossible. Sometime in the future the things might look obvious in the hindsight, but for now, they remain unanswered. From the various discussions, it was pretty clear that it was not the case of "unjustified pessimism."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The events are best covered by &lt;a href="http://capitalmind.in/2013/08/nsel-might-have-dummy-stocks-in-what-seems-to-be-a-financing-scheme/"&gt;CapitalMind&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://fundooprofessor.wordpress.com/2013/08/02/those-warehouse-receipts-again-and-what-to-do-about-them/"&gt;Prof. Bakshi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a conference call of &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=523716&amp;amp;con=1"&gt;Ashiana Housing&lt;/a&gt; later during the day. Brief inputs told that this is a real estate company which is &lt;em&gt;clean&lt;/em&gt;. At current levels, most real-estate companies look deeply under-valued, but hardly any of them want to share the wealth with their shareholders. It is clearly reflected by other real-estate companies' profit margins which are around 15%. Ashiana is among the few which have the margins of over 26% and which also provide proper pricing details on their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began with 2013 numbers as the revenues have dropped by almost half. The 2013 annual report answered: &lt;em&gt;"the year 2013 was low as expected. The reason being the change in accounting policy from POC (percentage of completion) to the contract completion method."&lt;/em&gt; This is a conservative accounting policy and seems to have hit the company even more as most of their earlier projects have just completed, and the new ones have just begun. The company recommends to use ECA (equivalent constructed area) and cash from operations as better comparative indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company does seem to have a very good &lt;a href="http://www.indianrealestateforum.com/real-estate-bhiwadi/t-ashiana-town-bhiwadi-24541.html"&gt;brand benefit&lt;/a&gt;. They don't sell through brokers (instead incentivizes the buyer if he comes through referral), restrict reselling upto 60% payment (approx 1.5 years) and treat land as raw-material (and not build up land banks). These can provide a very long term benefit to a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valuation wise, the company has a market capitalization of 360 Crores. There is a cash of 52 crores and a small loan of 11 crores. Thus the enterprise value is 319 crores. Against this, the company has an inventory of 231 crores. I am unsure about how much of it is the value of constructed area. I am also unsure about the percentage of constructed area to total salable area. The clarity on these two figures can give a good estimate about the value of total project, and consequently about the margin of safety available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualitatively the company looks great to keep an eye on. I will try to collect more details about the missing two figures tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.s: Found this &lt;a href="http://www.firstpost.com/economy/why-car-sales-are-falling-but-not-realty-prices-658909.html"&gt;interesting article&lt;/a&gt; while digging the above.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-02:day-5/</guid></item><item><title>Day 4</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-4/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I looked at &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=532493"&gt;Astral Microwave&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/day-2/"&gt;Day 2&lt;/a&gt;, while looking at defense companies. The stock looked interesting as it was showing a very good year-on-year growth and yet available at a multi-year low (at a market capitalization of 276 crores).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began reading the company's 2006 annual report. It was an exceptional year as the company's top-line grew by over 50%. Net profit that year was of 37 crores (and has stayed below it until 2013). That year company declared a 1:1 bonus (along with a stock split in 5:1 ratio). The R&amp;amp;D expenditure was 18% of revenue and the annual report was pretty optimistic about the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="From 2006 Annual Report" src="http://180stocks.github.io/static/uploads/astra_microwave.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the &lt;a href="http://www.moneycontrol.com/stock-charts/astramicrowaveproducts/charts/AMP01#AMP01"&gt;historical price&lt;/a&gt; chart to find that the market had been even more optimistic and had valued the company at whooping 1000 crores (37 times its annual earnings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year, company reported the &lt;em&gt;"end of major production orders of ground based radar sub-system which dominated both the top line and bottom line growth of the company in the last two financial years."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson of the day was never to overpay for a stock, no matter how tempting the prospects might be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At current levels, the stock is at 7 times its earnings, has &lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/Astra_Microwave_Products_Ltd_240713_Rst.pdf"&gt;book orders&lt;/a&gt; of 1000+ crores &lt;em&gt;"executable in the next 24 to 30 months"&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/corporates/Insider_Trading.aspx?scripcd=532493"&gt;promoters are buying&lt;/a&gt;. Words in the &lt;a href="http://nseindia.com/annual_reports/AR_ASTRAMICRO_2011_2012_03072012103025.zip"&gt;annual report (2012)&lt;/a&gt; have become more cautious and it does not seem that one might be "overpaying" at these levels. But, I will still like to miss this opportunity and will look for businesses which are lesser dependent on government.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-08-01:day-4/</guid></item><item><title>Day 3</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-3/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I started with &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=504966"&gt;Tinplate Company of India Ltd&lt;/a&gt;. It is a &lt;strong&gt;Tata Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;"largest indigenous producer of tin coated and tin free steel sheets in India"&lt;/em&gt;. The company has been in the business for over 90 years. Yet the &lt;strong&gt;market capitalization is only 358 crores&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a coincidence that today only I got a copy of the latest &lt;a href="http://www.capitalmarket.com/magazine/contents.asp?volno=28&amp;amp;Issno=11"&gt;Capital Market magazine&lt;/a&gt;. The cover story is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;"small forever."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The article covers the case-studies of &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=506685"&gt;Ultramarine &amp;amp; Pigments&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=509820"&gt;Paper Products Ltd&lt;/a&gt;. Both the companies have been into their business for decades, and yet have failed to scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of Ultramarine, &lt;em&gt;"though the company has reported profit over the last one decade; out of last 10 years, it reported decline in profit in five years."&lt;/em&gt; The reason associated is &lt;em&gt;"over-dependence on few clients."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper Products has multiple big FMCG clients including Levers, Nestle, Cadbury, Coca Cola etc. Yet the company hasn't been able to scale as it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;"is sandwiched between big customers on one hand and is a commodity play on the other hand."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to see that in both of the above cases, the companies were in a sort of commodity business and that their clients were big corporations. Thus the other party got to dictate the terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to Tinplate Company, tinplate is widely used in packaging industry. Infact 55% of the domestic demand is met through imports. But it is the other substitutes (tetra pack, pet, plastics as well as non-prime tin) that pose a major substitution threat due to their cost competitiveness. It is very similar to the above two cases of commodities and big customers. There is some hope for good growth in top-line but the growth in bottom-line looks doubtful. Valuations too don't look too cheap to provide a good margin of safety at these levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://180stocks.github.io/day-2/"&gt;Yesterday&lt;/a&gt; I also talked about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=532493"&gt;Astra Microwave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; while studying defense stocks. Well, I will need to delay it again for tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-07-31:day-3/</guid></item><item><title>Day 2</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-2/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One of my friends is in army and wants to invest into stocks. While talking to him over phone, I started looking at the listed companies into defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began with &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=533339"&gt;Zen Technologies&lt;/a&gt;. The company manufactures simulators and has a market capitalization of only 60 crores. The earnings have been very volatile over the years (63 crores in 2009 vs 17 crores in 2011 vs 100 crores in 2012 vs 40 crores in 2013). The company has an order book of &lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/ZEN_Technologies_Ltd_300513_Rst.pdf"&gt;37 crores&lt;/a&gt; and an OPM of around 30% (also very volatile). Company's recent buy back did bring some excitement, but it was a minor quantity of 17000 shares (0.19%). Due to the volatility in earnings of the company, I found it hard to derive some valuations for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/download/Research_Report/Report/533339/2012-13/BSE%20Company%20Research%20Report%20-%20Zen%20Technologies%20Ltd.pdf"&gt;CARE's report&lt;/a&gt; on Zen Technology mentioned about Bharat Electronics among the listed peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bharat_Electronics"&gt;Bharat Electronics&lt;/a&gt; is a PSU. It &lt;em&gt;"primarily manufactures advanced electronic products for the Indian Armed Forces."&lt;/em&gt; Market cap is just around 9000 crores with a cash of around 5000 crores in the March'13 &lt;a href="http://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/Bharat_Electronics_Ltd_300513.pdf"&gt;balance sheet&lt;/a&gt;. The annual profits are around 900 crores. This makes it a very attractive stock to follow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the risk here, as is with all the other PSUs, is that there are elections within the next 12 months. The experts believe that the cash from balance sheets of the PSUs will suddenly disappear. Some unnecessary deal, merger, expansion, subsidiary etc will happen and the cash will be gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barring the last year, the sales growth have been slow in the company. There are risks about the cash management, and a large distrust in promoters. For these reasons, I will watch this stock from a distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=532493"&gt;Astra Microwave&lt;/a&gt; looked good among other peers. I will cover it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-07-30:day-2/</guid></item><item><title>Day 1</title><link>http://180stocks.github.io/day-1/</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jenniferdewalt.com/index.html"&gt;Jennifer&lt;/a&gt; wanted to master web-development in 180 days. The way she proceeded was to build 1 website each day. That is crazy, and the &lt;a href="http://blog.jenniferdewalt.com/"&gt;results are fabulous&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to try the same craziness on stocks. Over the next half year, I will try to learn more about investing concepts, businesses and industries. Each day I will try to study at least 1 company and write a brief post about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up &lt;a href="http://www.screener.in/company/?q=532899"&gt;Kaveri Seeds&lt;/a&gt; for today. It is a seasonal company and its results are due within a week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has an excellent business. It provides high quality hybrid seeds which increases the crop's yield. In 2008, it introduced revolutionary hybrid BT-Cotton seeds, which provided wonderful returns not only to the farmers but also to the shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="http://www.kaveriseeds.in/AR-06-07.pdf"&gt;2007 annual report&lt;/a&gt; company mentioned that &lt;em&gt;"once a hybrid seed is developed and introduced, its acceptability gradually declines from year to year."&lt;/em&gt; Five years later, in the 2012 annual report it says &lt;em&gt;"cotton, considered by many as a mature market, we expect to gain market share because of our differentiated and high-yielding hybrid seeds portfolio."&lt;/em&gt; At the same time the company is optimistic about the developments in hybrid rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance sheet of the company is one of the most amazing ones. &lt;strong&gt;Of the total 858 crores of assets, 253 crores is financed from advance from customers. Another 237 crores is financed from creditors.&lt;/strong&gt; June quarter is the most important quarter for the company and thus the closing stock from March balance sheet gives a good estimate about the upcoming results. The March'13 inventory is Rs.491 crores (against 303 crores previous year). Going by these and the good monsoons, I estimate June sales to grow by anything between 30% to 75%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the above numbers, the forward PE is of around 9 to 12 times. At current PE of 16 (market cap of 2131 crores), it seems that the market has already discounted this upcoming quarter's growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes me concerned is that the company's annual report does not talk much about the business process. For a 2000 crore company, I expected the details about how the company's seeds are better and the differences in yields (some statistical and quantitative data). I also expected more details about the reasons for the robust growths (i.e whether the company expanded in new states or was it some real yield magic). Another little danger area is of lower taxation. This is one area where the peers (I checked Bayer Cropscience) seem more transparent about the processes and paying higher taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is enough &lt;a href="http://www.valuepickr.com/forum/not-so-hidden-gems/608487840"&gt;ground work&lt;/a&gt; available and I will take a little time to go through it. As it is a start, I find it hard to derive some intrinsic value for the company and thus will pick up a little smaller company for the next update.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">180Stocks</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>tag:180stocks.github.io,2013-07-29:day-1/</guid></item></channel></rss>